sunlife.ca 2009-10-15

# Sun Life Financial - Privacy

**Respecting your Privacy**

In this document, **you** and **your** mean the individual who is a customer or potential customer of a member of the [Sun Life Financial group of companies](http://www.sunlife.com/global/v/index.jsp?vgnextoid=5e48d284bf80e110VgnVCM100000abd2d09fRCRD&vgnextfmt=default&vgnLocale=en_CA) in Canada and **we** , **us** and **our** mean Sun Life Financial Inc., Sun Life Assurance Company of Canada, and their affiliates in Canada. 

_**Our commitment to protecting your privacy, our policy**_

Collecting personal information about you is essential to our ability to offer you high-quality investment, retirement and insurance products and to provide you with on-going service relating to your lifetime financial needs. We take great care to keep your personal information which we collect accurate, confidential and secure.

Our Policy sets high standards for collecting, using, disclosing and storing personal information. Sun Life Financial's Canadian Privacy Policy is complemented by our Privacy Code and by procedures to manage your personal information.

If you have any questions about Sun Life Financial's Canadian Privacy Policy and Privacy Code, please contact our Canadian Privacy Officer at (416) 408-8850 or by email at ["privacyofficer@sunlife.com"](mailto:privacyofficer@sunlife.com).

* * *

**Sun Life Financial's Privacy Policy For Canada**

How we collect, use and disclose personal information  
We will protect your personal information  
Your right to access your personal information  
Cookies  
For more information

**How we collect, use and disclose personal information**

**We ask you for only the information we need**

We collect only the information we need for the purposes we have identified to you.

Our files are kept for the purpose of providing and servicing financial and insurance products and services that we believe are right for you, over your lifetime.

We will not sell your personal information.

**Why we need the information**

Generally, we need to collect personal information to:

  * understand your needs,
  * determine your eligibility,
  * continue to offer you the full range of products and services that we believe meet your changing needs and to service such products and services,
  * meet regulatory or contractual requirements and implement risk management programs and procedures relating to the services and products provided to you.

We will make sure you understand why we need the information by using clear, understandable language.

**We will obtain your permission**

We collect, use or disclose your personal information with your permission.

Your permission may be expressed in writing or be implied and you may give it to us verbally, electronically, or through your authorized representative.

You may withdraw your permission to collect, use and disclose your personal information at any time, subject to legal and contractual restrictions and reasonable notice.

Where medical information about you is collected or released, we will obtain your consent to do so. We will not share it with other members of the Sun Life Financial group of companies.

Before we make information available to third parties, other than an agent or service provider who needs it, we will tell you at the time we obtain your consent or before we make the information available, who those persons or organizations are, the kind of information we want to share with them and why.

**We will limit how long we keep information**

We will keep your personal information as long as it is necessary, including updating the product or service or as required by law.

When we destroy personal information, we will use safeguards to prevent unauthorized parties from gaining access to the information during the process.

**We will protect your personal information**

**We are responsible for your information**

We are responsible for all personal information in our possession, including information transferred to a third-party service provider or agent, so that we can provide you with a product or service. In some instances our employees, service providers, agents, reinsurers and any of their service providers, may be located in jurisdictions outside Canada, and your personal information may be subject to the laws of those foreign jurisdictions.  All such persons, whether or not they are located in Canada, are required to protect the confidentiality of your personal information in a manner that is consistent with our privacy policy and practices.

**How we protect information**

Access to your personal information is restricted to those of Sun Life Financial's employees, agents and authorized service providers who need it to do their jobs.

We have developed and are continuing to enhance security procedures to safeguard and protect personal information against loss, theft, unauthorized disclosure, copying, and unauthorized use or modification. We will maintain appropriate safeguards and security procedures that reflect the types of documents, including electronic or paper records, organizational measures including security clearances and limiting access on a "need-to-know" basis, and technological measures such as the use of passwords and encryption. While we endeavour to protect all information, the most sensitive information, such as medical information, receives the highest level of protection. 

**Your right to access your personal information**

**Your rights**

You have the right to ask whether we hold any personal information about you and to see that information, as provided by law. Where we have obtained medical information about you from a third-party, we will release this information only through your physician.

You also have the right to know:

  * how we collected your personal information,
  * how we are using it, and
  * to whom it may have been disclosed.

**How to request an update or correction**

If you believe any of the information we have collected about you is incorrect or incomplete, you have the right to ask us to change it.

If you show that your personal information is inaccurate or incomplete, we will make the necessary changes.

If you feel we have not dealt with your request to your satisfaction, you can follow our complaint resolution procedures.

**How to register complaints**

You may register a privacy-related complaint by contacting Sun Life Financial's Canadian Privacy Officer. We will explain Sun Life Financial's Canadian complaint procedure to you and investigate all complaints. If a complaint is justified, we will take all appropriate steps to set the situation right, including changing our policies and practices if necessary. We will also let you know what other complaint procedures may be available to you.

**Cookies**

**What are cookies?**

A cookie is a small file used by a Web server to store information in your browser's temporary memory or on your computer. Cookies cannot access other information or files from your computer. There are two types of cookies - a **session cookie** and a **permanent cookie**. A session cookie (sometimes referred to as a transient cookie) is erased when you close your Internet browser and leave our website. A "permanent cookie" is a file that remains on your computer when you close your Internet browser. Permanent cookies have expiry dates and will automatically be deleted from your computer after their expiry date or alternatively you can clear your stored cookies via your browser preferences on your computer. A permanent cookie can be read only by the website that created the cookie when you visit that site again. We use both session cookies and permanent cookies within our websites.

**Why are cookies used?**

Cookies are very common, with many organizations electing to use them to gather data regarding how visitors explore their websites - information such as how many new visitors there are, how many repeat visitors there are, how many sections or pages of the website a visitor explores and so forth. Organizations use the information gathered by cookies to modify their websites to improve their website's performance and functionality.

Cookies have the ability to identify a visitor, if the visitor has used a website's login feature.With a permanent cookie your login ID would be stored in an encrypted format on your computer, so that the next time you visit the website you would be recognized when you sign in. This enables the website to recall your preferences and provide a more customized experience.

**What are your options regarding cookies?**

You have the ability to decide whether you want to accept all cookies, reject all cookies or simply be notified when a cookie will be created. To do this you need to alter your browser preferences. Since the procedure for altering preferences varies by browser  you should check the 'Help' menu of your browser to learn how to alter your cookie preferences.

**For more information**

For more information, please contact Sun Life Financial's Privacy Officer in Canada at (416) 408-8850 or by email at [privacyofficer@sunlife.com](mailto:privacyofficer@sunlife.com).

* * *

**Sun Life Financial's Privacy Code For Canada**  
  
---  
  
**Principle 1 - Accountability**

Each member, employee or agent of the Sun Life Financial group of companies in Canada is responsible for personal information under his or her control and each member company shall designate an individual or individuals to be accountable for compliance with this Code.

**Principle 2 - Identifying Purposes**

The purposes for which personal information is collected shall be identified before or at the time the information is collected.

**Principle 3 - Consent**

The prior knowledge and permission of the individual are required for the collection, use or disclosure of personal information, except for legal or security reasons.

**Principle 4 - Limiting Collection**

The collection of personal information shall be limited to that which is necessary for the purposes identified. Personal information shall be collected by fair and lawful means.

**Principle 5 - Limiting Use, Disclosure and Retention**

Personal information will not be used, disclosed or retained for purposes other than those for which the information was collected, except with the permission of the individual, or as permitted or required by law.

| 

**Principle 6 - Accuracy**

Personal information shall be as accurate, complete and current as is necessary for the identified purposes for which it is to be used.

**Principle 7 - Safeguarding Information**

Personal information will be protected by safeguards appropriate to the sensitivity of the information.

**Principle 8 - Openness**

Members of the Sun Life Financial group of companies will make readily available to their customers specific information about our policies and procedures relating to the management of their personal information.

**Principle 9 - Individual Access**

Upon request, an individual will be informed of the existence, use and disclosure of his or her personal information and shall be given access to it. An individual will be able to challenge the accuracy and completeness of the information and have it amended as appropriate.

**Principle 10 - Handling Customer Complaints and Suggestions**

Individuals can address any complaint regarding compliance with the above principles with our Privacy Officer.[privacyofficer@sunlife.com](mailto:privacyofficer@sunlife.com)  
  
...Back to top
